A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Countries, Series E FA341
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Italy
  - Italy - Association of Friends of Brera; NAR - Honorary Triennial Member (Florentine Flood Relief), 1966-1968 (Box 46, Folder 382)
    Memos re: NAR contribution to help rehabilitate art works damaged in 1966 Florentine flood. Correspondence re: NAR's receiving honorary Triennial membership in the Association of Friends of Brera.
  - Italy - Buoncompagni Ludovisi, Prince Alberico & Princess Laetitia, 1959-1967 (Box 46, Folder 383)
    Informal personal correspondence.
  - Italy - Churches, 1950-1969 (Box 46, Folder 384)
  - Italy - Colleges and Schools, 1959-1968 (Box 46, Folder 385)
  - Italy - Colleges - The International University for Social Realism - Father Morlion, 1952-1957 (Box 46, Folder 386)
    Appeal to NAR, David and Winthrop Rockefeller for funds for an anti-Communist education and action program. Henry Luce supported the project and contacted NAR in 1957. Appeals declined.
  - Italy - Crespi, Mario, 1957 (Box 46, Folder 387)
    NAR congratulated Crespi for award he received.
  - Italy - Government, 1967 (Box 46, Folder 388)
    Memo re: NAR appointment with Rumor, prominent politician. NAR letter of congratulations to Italian consul in New York appointed ambassador to Uruguay.
  - Italy - Mattiolo, Dr. Raffaele, 1950-1969 (Box 46, Folder 389)
    Italian businessman and bank president. Friend of NAR. Informal correspondence re: art and possible exhibits in New York. NAR letters of thanks for various gifts. Letter from NAR outlining his appointment by the President as head of Board for International Development.
  - Italy - The Vatican - Roman Catholic Church, 1963-1965 (Box 46, Folder 390)
    Correspondence, memos and telegrams re: NAR trip to the Vatican and audience with Pope Paul and Pope's trip to New York. Exchange of letters of thanks between NAR and Pope. Thanks NAR for gifts.
- Jamaica
  Jamaica
  - Jamaica, B. W. I. - General Correspondence (A-L), 1951-1969 (Box 46, Folder 391)
  - Jamaica, B. W. I. - General Correspondence (M-Z), 1951-1969 (Box 46, Folder 392)
- Japan
  Japan
  - Japan - General, 1946-1971 (Box 47, Folder 393)
    Appeals. Declined. Informal correspondence with acquaintances.
  - Japan - Aikawa, Yoshisuke - Smaller Enterprises Promotion Company, Ltd., 1957-1962 (Box 47, Folder 394)
    Japanese businessman. Supreme Economic Advisor to the Head of State. Unsuccessfully sought Rockefeller backing for project to expand Japanese exports by expanding small business enterprises. Memoranda and correspondence re: meeting between Aikawa and Rockefeller staff people and possible contributions to Aikawa project.
  - Japan - Colleges and Schools, 1960-1962 (Box 47, Folder 395)
  - Japan - Government, 1966-1969 (Box 47, Folder 396)
    Letters from NAR to Japanese ambassador and consul re: New York State International Division of Commerce. Memos re: Prime Minister Sato's visit to the United States.
  - Japan - Hasegawa, N. and Prince Takamatsu, 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 397)
    Hasegawa was a director of the Sumiton Chemical Company, Prince Takamatsu a member of the imperial family and friend of Hasegawa. File consists of correspondence among NAR, Hasegawa, the Prince re: Hasegawa's business concerns and projects, United States-Japanese relations, Japanese post-war developments. Requests for NAR and Rockefeller Foundation support. Copies of papers from the Prince on international issues.
  - Japan - Lane, Dr. Richard, 1966-1968 (Box 47, Folder 398)
    Sent copies to NAR of "Monumento Nipponica."
- Korea
  Korea
  - Korea - General, 1950-1970 (Box 47, Folder 399)
    Appeals. Declined. Scattered material re: Korean War, including memo to NAR on lack of Latin American reaction, some printed material and remarks by South Korea on Chinese entry into Korean War.
  - Korea - Chungang University - Yim, Dr. Louise, 1947-1971 (Box 48, Folder 400)
    Representative at United Nations for South Korea. Headed school in Seoul. Clippings, appeals for Rockefeller support of her school and other projects.
  - Korea - Lt. General John R. Hodge, undated (Box 48, Folder 401)
- Laos
  Laos
  - Laos - Laos, Kingdom of, 1963 (Box 48, Folder 402)
    Program put out by State Department for visit to United States of Laotian King.
- Latin America
  Latin America
  - Latin America - General, 1947-1969 (Box 48, Folder 403)
    Appeals. Declined. Copy of 1959 statement by NAR on his interest in Latin America, apparently prepared in reply to a request from a newspaper.
  - Latin America - Clippings, 1947-1953 (Box 48, Folder 404)
    Clippings re: Latin American affairs.
  - Latin America - Report of Latin American (probably from Chase Manhattan Bank), March 1937 (Box 48, Folder 405)
    Series of small descriptive reports on Latin American countries - politics, economics, society.
- Lebanon
  Lebanon
  - Lebanon - General (A-Z), 1947-1971 (Box 48, Folder 406)
- Liechtenstein
  liechtenstein
  - Liechtenstein - Furstentum Liechtenstein, 1965 (Box 48, Folder 407)
- Luxembourg
  Luxembourg
  - Luxembourg - General, 1964 (Box 48, Folder 408)
- Mexico
  Mexico
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (A), 1944-1971 (Box 48, Folder 409)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (B), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 410)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (Ca), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 411)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (Ce-Cu), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 412)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (D), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 413)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (E), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 414)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (F), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 415)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (G), 1945-1971 (Box 49, Folder 416)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (H), 1945-1971 (Box 50, Folder 417)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (I-L), 1945-1971 (Box 50, Folder 418)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (M), 1945-1971 (Box 50, Folder 419)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (N-O), 1945-1971 (Box 50, Folder 420)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (P-Q), 1945-1971 (Box 50, Folder 421)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (R), 1945-1971 (Box 51, Folder 422)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (S), 1945-1971 (Box 51, Folder 423)
  - Mexico - General Correspondence (T-Z), 1945-1971 (Box 51, Folder 424)
  - Mexico - de Alba, Pedro, 1947 (Box 51, Folder 425)
    Informal correspondence with NAR containing general reference to United States-Mexican relations.
  - Mexico - President Aleman, Miguel, 1946-1952 (Box 51, Folder 426)
    President of Mexico, 1946-1952. Correspondence re: NAR's attendance at inauguration in 1946, Aleman's visit to United States. File also included copies of speeches, menus from Aleman's United States visits, printed material re: Aleman's 1946 campaign for President of Mexico.
  - Mexico - Beteta, Ramon, 1947-1950 (Box 51, Folder 427)
    Government leader; held economic posts in Mexican government. Letter to NAR requesting copy of NAR introduction of Beteta in St. Louis. Other informal correspondence.
  - Mexico - Chavez, Carlos, 1945-1961 (Box 51, Folder 428)
    Director, National Institute of Fine Arts and Literature. Correspondence between Chavez and NAR re: art matters, including Diego Rivera exhibit in Mexican National Museum. Clippings and other informal correspondence.
  - Mexico - Churches, 1955-1970 (Box 51, Folder 429)
  - Mexico - Colina, Rafael de la, 1944-1958 (Box 51, Folder 430)
    Ambassador of Mexico. Informal correspondence, requests for appointments.
  - Mexico - Colleges and Schools, 1947-1971 (Box 51, Folder 431)
  - Mexico - American School of Mexico City, 1956-1957 (Box 52, Folder 432)
  - Mexico - Covarrubias, Rosa, Mrs., 1941-1960 (Box 52, Folder 433)
    Personal correspondence. Asked NAR to speak to President Lopez Mateos of Mexico re: court case in which she was involved.
  - Mexico - Del Rio Canedo, Francisco, 1945 (Box 52, Folder 434)
    Requests NAR to write letters of recommendation for son. Copies of NAR letter and correspondence between MIT (Massachusetts Institute of Technology) and Tufts and NAR re: the candidate.
  - Mexico - Frente Popular Anti-Communista de Mexico, Florencio Avila Sanchez, 1952-1960 (Box 52, Folder 435)
    Memoranda, circular letters mimeographed and printed literature stressing the dangers and degree of Communist infiltration into Mexican and Western Hemisphere affairs. Many clippings mostly in Spanish. Appeals. Declined.
  - Mexico - Government, 1946-1970 (Box 52, Folder 436)
    NAR congratulations to President Echeverri on his inauguration. NAR regrets on not attending President Lopez Mateos inauguration, 1952. Press releases re: presidential campaign of 1946. Printed material.
  - Mexico - Oil Expropriation, 1939 (Box 52, Folder 437)
    Memorandum of conversation between Mexican President Cardenas and NAR in the presence of Mr. Walter Douglas and his secretary, October 14-15, 1939. In memo NAR reports Cardenas as saying he foresaw little hope of a settlement with the oil companies, that expropriation of oil properties was an effort to lift Mexican morale. Discussion also included Rockefeller Foundation problems in working with the Mexican Health Department. Also, NAR handwritten notes and draft of an extensive memorandum to State Department reporting Mexico's willingness to compensate oil companies and agreement by the companies and Mexico to hold talks.
  - Mexico - Hospitals, 1962-1971 (Box 52, Folder 438)
    Appeals to Rockefeller Brothers Fund, Rockefeller Foundation, and NAR. Declined.
  - Mexico - Monasterio, J.M.O., Credito International, S. A., Mexico City, 1948-1968 (Box 53, Folder 439)
    Banker and businessman. Informal correspondence including congratulations to NAR for his part in Nixon election, 1968. Felt Nixon would have good fiscal policy. Personal correspondence, informal correspondence re: bank business; asks NAR for suggestions for a new job.
  - Mexico - Palvicini, F. F., 1945-1950 (Box 53, Folder 440)
    NAR letters of thanks for articles and books written by Palvicini, sent to NAR. Copies of items sent.
  - Mexico - Printed Material, 1949 (Box 53, Folder 441)
    National Foreign Trade Council Report on Mexican Development.
  - Mexico - Reza Castanos, Gaspar, 1954-1969 (Box 53, Folder 442)
    Collector of paintings. Correspondence with NAR office making various requests in connection with his collection. All declined.
  - Mexico - Rockefeller Foundation Corn Commission-Agreement, 1947, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 443)
    Clippings and printed material dealing with Corn Commission's work and Rockefeller Foundation support for it. 1950 Rockefeller Foundation report titled "Mexican Agricultural Program."
  - Mexico - Spratling, William, 1944-1963 (Box 53, Folder 444)
    Involved in art projects. Asks NAR about Museum of Modern Art, Museum of Primitive Art, assistance to back his book on jade, sends NAR art books, catalogues of exhibits with which he was involved. NAR, on his request, sent letter recommending him for an honorary degree at Auburn. Memo to NAR from NAR staff re: Spratling's gold collection.
  - Mexico - Universidad Femenina de Mexico, Sra. Adela Santacilla, 1944 (Box 53, Folder 445)
    Clippings, posters, printed material, photographs. Almost all in Spanish.
  - Mexico - Viesca, Jorge, 1947 (Box 53, Folder 446)
    Private secretary to the President of Mexico. Letter introducing his physician to NAR and asking NAR to help the doctor in a project he was undertaking in the United States.
  - Mexico - Villasenor, Eduardo, 1944-1965 (Box 53, Folder 447)
    Banker and businessman. Correspondence between NAR and Villasenor re: possible Rockefeller backing for a banking project. Asked NAR advice on United Nations project he headed re: technical assistance for Cuba (1952). NAR letters of thanks for books and reports he sent NAR. Copies of items sent.
- Morocco
  Morocco
  - Morocco - General, 1965-1971 (Box 54, Folder 448)
- Near East
  Middle East
  - Near East - General, 1957-1968 (Box 54, Folder 449)
    Appeals. Declined. Memos to Mrs. Boyer from Mr. Creel and Mr. Hyde suggesting a NAR contribution to nonpolitical project to aid victims of the 1967 Mid East War. David Rockefeller was a director of the project. Copy of report by William Ronan on Near Eastern nations' legal and administrative systems.
- Newfoundland
  Newfoundland and Labrador
  - Newfoundland - General, 1950 (Box 54, Folder 450)
    Informal letter to Mr. Joseph Smallwood.
- New Guinea
  Papua New Guinea
  - New Guinea - Territory of Papua and New Guinea, 1966-1971 (Box 54, Folder 451)
- New Zealand
  New Zealand
  - New Zealand - General, 1939-1970 (Box 54, Folder 452)
    Appeals. Declined. Correspondence and memos re: NAR's assistance to Dr. Elizabeth Gunn in locating her sons who were in New York City (1939).
- Nicaragua
  Nicaragua
  - Nicaragua - General (A-L), 1945-1971 (Box 54, Folder 453)
    Appeals. Declined. Routine correspondence re: visits of Nicaraguan ex-president and president.
  - Nicaragua - General (M-Z), 1945-1971 (Box 54, Folder 454)
    Appeals. Declined. Routine correspondence re: visits of Nicaraguan ex-president and president. Condolences to President-elect of Nicaragua, General Anastasia Somoza on death of his brother, ex-President Luis Somoza.
  - Nicaragua - Sevilla Sacasa, G., 1947-1971 (Box 54, Folder 455)
    Nicaraguan Ambassador to the United States. Telegrams to NAR wishing a happy July 4th. NAR letter to Inter-American Alliance applauding the alliance's naming Sevilla Sacasa Man of the Decade.
- Norway
  Norway
  - Norway - General, 1953-1970 (Box 54, Folder 456)
  - Norway - Lie, Trygvie and Mrs., 1948-1968 (Box 55, Folder 457)
    Secretary-General of the United Nations. Copies of Lie's speeches sent to NAR, memo to NAR from frank Jamieson on Lie's memoirs, Lie's request that NAR find out why Lie's memoirs were not bought by United States missions abroad and NAR correspondence between NAR and Lie. Obituary clipping and NAR condolences to family.
  - Norway - Rasmussen, Kristian Thorhild, 1959 (Box 55, Folder 458)
    Father of Anne-Marie Rasmussen Rockefeller, Steven Rockefeller's wife. Correspondence re: K. Rasmussen's visit to United States, including invitations to him while in New York, his thanks to NAR for hospitality.
- Pakistan
  Pakistan
  - Pakistan - General, 1953-1971 (Box 55, Folder 459)
- Palestine
  - Palestine - General, 1948-1951 (Box 55, Folder 460)
    Letter to NAR from Emergency Palestine Committee asking NAR support for partition. Printed material, 1950-1951 re: Israel.
  - Palestine - Jerusalem, Hospitals, 1948-1949 (Box 55, Folder 461)
  - Palestine - Palestine Archaeological Museum, Jerusalem, 1947-1970 (Box 55, Folder 462)
    Appeals. Declined. Consideration of NAR contribution to restore church tower damaged in 1967.
  - Palestine - Palestine General Counsel for Social Welfare, 1948 (Box 55, Folder 463)
    Appeal for American International Association for Social and Economic Development (AIA) funds for relief work on behalf of the Palestinian people. AIA funds refused; NAR sent personal contribution.
- Panama
  Panama
  - Panama - General Correspondence, 1947-1974 (Box 55, Folder 464)
  - Panama - De La Guardia, Ernesto, Jr., 1956-1969 (Box 55, Folder 465)
    Correspondence among NAR, La Guardia and Eugene Black of World Bank re: Panamanian loan, appointment of a Panamanian to the bank, and a related political crisis in Panama. Reference to President La Guardia's anti-corruption drive. Copies of correspondence between Ogden Reid and Panamanian and Canal Zone officials re: loan agreements. Informal correspondence between NAR office and La Guardia's.
  - Panama - Government, 1948-1970 (Box 55, Folder 466)
    1948 memo to NAR on crisis in presidential succession in Panama. 1970 memo re: Panamanian request for U. S. helicopters; clippings and memos on economy and politics.
  - Panama - Remon, Cecilia P. de, Mrs., 1956-1961 (Box 55, Folder 467)
    Minister of Labor, Social Welfare, and Public Health, friend of NAR. Correspondence with NAR re: items Mrs. Remon requested from Museum of Modern Art. Personal correspondence.
  - Panama - Vallarino, Joaquin J., Dr., 1945-1968 (Box 55, Folder 468)
    Panamanian Ambassador to the United States, 1945-1948 and 1952-1956. Personal correspondence and exchanges of congratulations between NAR and Vallarino. Vallarino requests for NAR help with admissions for men to Dartmouth and Annapolis. Copy of NAR letters for candidates. Memo by NAR staff to NAR re: Vallarino's withdrawal as a presidential candidate in 1948. Copy of Vallarino proposal for American Association of Nations.
- Paraguay
  Paraguay
  - Paraguay - General, 1945-1970 (Box 55, Folder 469)
    Appeals. Declined. Memo to NAR from Berent Friele on presidency of General Stroessner. Correspondence between NAR and Ambassador to United States Velasquez, related inter-office memoranda concerning Paraguay's award to NAR of the National Order of Merit. NAR did not wish to accept medal from Velasquez because of the character of the Paraguayan government but did apparently accept it from the next ambassador.
- Peru
  Peru
  - Peru - General (A-C), 1946-1970 (Box 56, Folder 470)
    Appeals. Declined. Office memoranda suggesting NAR not congratulate Boza on his presidential candidacy.
  - Peru - General (D-G), 1946-1970 (Box 56, Folder 471)
  - Peru - General (H-N), 1946-1970 (Box 56, Folder 472)
  - Peru - General (O-Q), 1946-1970 (Box 56, Folder 473)
    Appeals. Declined. NAR condolences to wife on death of ex-president Prado.
  - Peru - General (R-Z), 1946-1970 (Box 56, Folder 474)
  - Peru - Beltran, Pedro G., 1945-1968 (Box 57, Folder 475)
    Newspaper editor, premier and minister of finance. Correspondence re: Beltran interest in housing, his desire on trip to United States to talk to people in U.S. Housing and Home Finance Agency. Memos and reports on Beltran's politically-inspired imprisonment in 1956. Clippings re: Beltran's becoming premier and finance minister in 1959.
  - Peru - Bustamente, J. Luis, 1945-1950 (Box 57, Folder 476)
    President of Peru, 1945-1948. Deposed in 1948. Copies of Bustamente speeches sent to NAR by various people. Appraisals of Bustamente regime by NAR associates. Clipping with interview of exiled ex-president staying in New York.
  - Peru - Colleges and Schools, 1952-1968 (Box 57, Folder 477)
  - Peru - Peru Earthquake, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 478)
    Telegram asking NAR aid in heading relief program. NAR reply.
  - Peru - Fernandez Soler, Antenor, 1946-1948 (Box 57, Folder 479)
    Requests for appointments with NAR. Requests for NAR in getting Standard Oil to deliver an oil shipment to a client of his.
  - Peru - Garcia-Sayan, E., 1947-1949 (Box 57, Folder 480)
    Foreign Minister of Bustamente government. Informal correspondence with NAR. Correspondence asking NAR's help in finding a job following the overthrow of the Bustamente government. NAR correspondence re: job at International Basic Economy Corporation, with United Nations for Garcia-Sayan.
  - Peru - Government, 1969 (Box 57, Folder 481)
    Memoranda from Berent Friele to NAR re: Peruvian Government dispute with International Petroleum Co.
  - Peru - Haya de la Torre, Victor Raul, 1946-1951 (Box 57, Folder 482)
    Writer. Leader of the Aprista Party. Personal correspondence with NAR. Appeals to NAR for earthquake relief aid. Briefing memo to NAR meeting with Haya de la Torre. Memo to NAR and clipping re: International Court decision disapproving Haya de la Torre asylum in Colombian Embassy.
  - Peru - Hospitals, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 483)
    Printed material, in Spanish.
  - Peru - Lima, Hospitals - El Hojar de la Madre, 1949 (Box 57, Folder 484)
  - Peru - Moscoso, Guillermo, 1953 (Box 57, Folder 485)
    Worked for International Petroleum Company in Lima. Sent NAR clippings re: United States Senator Allan Ellender's Peruvian visit, news conference and anti-Communist speech by President Odria of Peru.
  - Peru - Saco Miro Zuesada, Alfredo, 1948 (Box 57, Folder 486)
    Chairman, National Food and Nutrition Board. NAR notified by State Department of his visit to United States and wrote him.
  - Peru - University Mayor de San Marcos, 1950-1961 (Box 57, Folder 487)
    Correspondence between University and NAR re: Museum of Modern Art sending art prints for exhibit. Prints were sent.
  - Peru - Zarate, Rodrigo, Dr., 1952-1963 (Box 58, Folder 488)
    Peruvian Senator. Coordinator of Inter-Parliamentary Foreign Relations. Proposed meeting of representatives of universities throughout the Americas. Other proposals over the years, some enacted honoring John Davison Rockefeller, the Rockefeller Foundation and the work of the Rockefellers in general.
- Philippines
  Philippines
  - Philippine Islands - General (A-C), 1955-1971 (Box 58, Folder 489)
  - Philippine Islands - General (D-L), 1955-1971 (Box 58, Folder 490)
  - Philippine Islands - General (M-P), 1955-1971 (Box 58, Folder 491)
  - Philippine Islands - General (Q-S), 1955-1971 (Box 58, Folder 492)
  - Philippine Islands - General (T-Z), 1955-1971 (Box 58, Folder 493)
  - Philippine Islands - Arellano, O. J. - Operation Brotherhood - Asian School for Leadership, 1955-1958 (Box 59, Folder 494)
    Appeals. Thanks for John Davison Rockefeller 3rd contribution to school. Correspondence re: Rockefeller Foundation unfavorable consideration of the school for grant.
  - Philippine Islands - Churches, 1952-1970 (Box 59, Folder 495)
  - Philippine Islands - Colleges and Schools, 1958-1971 (Box 59, Folder 496)
  - Philippine Islands - Magsaysay Family, 1958 (Box 59, Folder 497)
    Correspondence among Jesus Magsaysay, NAR and NAR office, and "Reader's Digest" re: J. Magsaysay's proposal for a biography of his brother, the late Philippine President Ramon Magsaysay.
  - Philippine Islands - Otigas, Francisco, Jr., 1958-1971 (Box 59, Folder 498)
- Poland
  Poland
  - Poland - General, 1958-1971 (Box 59, Folder 499)
  - Poland - Braun, Jerzy, Dr., 1966 (Box 59, Folder 500)
    Appeals for funds for medical equipment. Referred to Rockefeller Brothers Fund. Declined.
- Portugal
  Portugal
  - Portugal - General Correspondence (A-I), 1958-1971 (Box 59, Folder 501)
  - Portugal - General Correspondence (L-Z), 1958-1971 (Box 59, Folder 502)
  - Portugal - Possollo, Guilherme - Fundaco Ricardo do Esprito Santo Silva, 1969-1970 (Box 59, Folder 503)
    Correspondence between NAR and Mr. Possollo, director of the school. NAR ordered furniture and decorations. Mr. Possollo asked NAR's help in finding out what happened re: a proposed "New York Times" article on the school.
- Puerto Rico
  Puerto Rico
  - Puerto Rico - General Correspondence (A-D), 1949-1971 (Box 59, Folder 504)
    Appeals and miscellaneous correspondence. Appeals generally declined. Newspapers and magazines sent to NAR.
  - Puerto Rico - General Correspondence (E-R), 1949-1971 (Box 60, Folder 505)
  - Puerto Rico - General Correspondence (S-Z), 1949-1971 (Box 60, Folder 506)
  - Puerto Rico - Hospitals, 1959 (Box 60, Folder 507)
    Invitation and appeals, declined.
  - Puerto Rico - Mososo, Teodoro, 1949-1961 (Box 60, Folder 508)
    Served as United States Ambassador to Venezuela and administrator of the Economic Development Administration of Puerto Rico; correspondence re: miscellaneous matters including son's education and transportation.
  - Puerto Rico - Munoz Marin, Luis, 1948-1963 (Box 60, Folder 509)
    Served as Governor of Puerto Rico; invitation to attend inauguration; other invitations also declined; birthday greetings.
  - Puerto Rico - Schools and Colleges, 1954-1969 (Box 60, Folder 510)
  - Puerto Rico - San Juan Todos Little League Baseball Team (Box 60, Folder 511)
    Correspondence re: team and NAR support of travel.
    See also: Puerto Rico - Flamm Todos Little League Baseball Team.
- Romania
  ROmania
  - Romania, 1965-1971 (Box 60, Folder 512)
- Scotland